=Blossoms of Power=
(Adapted from the novel, After My
Bloom, All Flowers Wither by Jin Huang)
=Episode 14=
(Gudu Garden)
Here.
- Kick it to me.
- Brother, I want to play too.
Thank you, Brother.
Let me play!
Nanny Liu.
Nanny Liu,
why is there bloody water?
What a tragedy.
One of the children is badly injured.
Nanny, don't panic.
I'll go take a look right now.
You must be
Commandery Princess Zhaoning.
How did you get hurt so badly?
I am Qi Pei.
From Li County, Shunan.
My older brother owed gambling debts,
and was thrown into prison
in Zenan District.
But he never gambles.
When I went to visit him,
he had vanished into thin air.
I sought help everywhere to no avail,
so I had to come to the capital
to appeal to the Emperor.
As a result, I was hunted down
all the way here.
Do you have any evidence?
The officials in Zenan
protect each other,
and distort the truth.
The evidence I collected
was tricked out of me and destroyed.
They must have caught up with me.
Mo Yu, protect Qi Pei.
We'll go out together.
Yes.
There's tung oil in the water.
These deranged thugs
dare to commit crimes so openly!
Hurry.
Mo Yu, stay close to me!
Yes.
Come.
- Protect His Highness!
- The guards are here! Retreat!
- Hurry!
- Protect His Highness!
Imperial Guards, hear my command!
There are assassins
in the courtyard. Arrest them all.
Don't let a single one escape.
- Yes.
Go!
Commandery Princess!
Qi Pei is a crucial witness.
Keep him safe.
Don't worry.
Everything will be fine.
Commandery Princess!
Your Highness,
Commandery Princess went
to Gudu Garden to care for the orphans,
and encountered a fire.
Where is she now?
How is she doing?
She was rescued.
She is not seriously hurt.
Who saved her?
I will reward them handsomely.
It was Prince Lie.
Drink your medicine.
The Duke's manor is heavily guarded,
yet you can come and go as you please.
It seems you are not only
in good health,
but also highly skilled in martial arts.
We are destined
to be husband and wife after all.
Naturally, I have no need
to hide anything from you.
Drink your medicine.
Are you forcing me
to feed it to you with my lips?
I never yield to threats.
I have been very restrained.
I don't want to offend you,
nor do I want you to despise me.
Xiao Huayong.
Commandery Princess Zhaoning,
who always prioritizes the big picture,
abandoned me
to choose another.
But who else
is a better match for you than me,
who has a legitimate imperial descent
and a short life expectancy?
Legitimate imperial descent
can be changed.
Whether your life is short or not
can be orchestrated.
Get out.
Don't be angry, Commandery Princess.
It's my fault.
Get some good rest.
I'll handle the rest.
As for Changying,
you don't need to thank him in person.
Your Highness,
aren't you just making the
Commandery Princess angry for nothing?
When I heard she was in danger,
I was worried sick.
And I blamed myself,
wishing I had been the one to save her.
I felt so powerless and anxious
that I lost my composure for a moment.
In all these years,
you've never been like this.
Are we returning to the palace?
No.
We're going to deliver a gift.
I happened to see her going
to Gudu Garden today,
so I quietly followed her.
At least I could be
a little closer to her.
I didn't expect to save her.
Changying,
knowing the road ahead is doomed,
yet still embracing it willingly...
I understand that feeling, too.
I won't try to persuade you anymore.
I couldn't anyway.
Changqing...
Your Highness,
the Crown Prince is here.
Greetings, Your Highness.
We are brothers.
No need for formalities.
Your Highness, to what do we owe
the honor of your visit?
Do you have any orders for us?
I just came from Duke of Wei's Manor.
The Commandery Princess asked me
to thank you on her behalf
for saving her, Changying.
This is between
the Commandery Princess and me.
You did her a great favor.
But men and women
should keep their distance.
She wishes to avoid suspicion,
which is why she asked me
to thank you on her behalf.
Since the gift has been delivered...
There's no rush.
This is Commandery Princess's gift
of gratitude.
My gift of gratitude
hasn't been delivered yet.
(Minister Song...)
This letter seems to be a secret missive
from Noble Consort Rong
to win over court officials.
Noble Consort Rong
is working so tirelessly
to gather trusted followers
for you, Changying.
What a deep bond between mother and son.
But I fear it might carry the suspicion
of forming factions for personal gain.
Your Highness,
you're incredibly resourceful,
but these letters are just
about trivial family matters.
They hardly count as forming factions.
And Changying knows absolutely nothing
about them.
Is that so?
But I have dozens
of such letters in my palace.
I naturally believe
what you say, Changqing.
But will others
believe it?
As for this gift from you,
Changying and I are deeply grateful.
We accept it.
Changqing.
Whatever you two brothers intend to do,
I won't interfere.
But as for my woman,
no one is allowed
to lay a finger on her.
Farewell, Your Highness.
Didn't I say it?
We are brothers.
No need for formalities.
Changqing,
these letters can't convict us.
Why let him threaten us?
The Crown Prince
usually just holds back.
Even without these letters,
he would have other ways
to make you back down.
You just have to steer clear
of him for now.
However...
However what?
He came in such a hurry today
and even used letters to threaten us.
This shows that his marriage
with Zhaoning
has hit a snag.
Otherwise,
why would he go to such lengths?
So he hasn't won
Zhaoning's heart either.
The omnipotent Crown Prince
is also just suffering
from unrequited love.
Young Master,
the witness sent
by the Commandery Princess
has been settled in.
Make sure he is well taken care of.
There must be no mistakes.
Rest assured, Young Master.
Li County is under
Shunan's jurisdiction.
I absolutely refuse to believe
that under my father's governance,
such a despicable crime
could happen in Shunan.
Yes, I don't believe it either.
But
why are you packing your bags?
I'm going back
to thoroughly investigate this matter.
You're investigating?
Isn't the imperial court
sending someone?
Within the imperial court,
there are many
who covet Shunan's military power.
I know this better than anyone
from my years in the capital.
This case is murky.
If someone uses it as a pretext,
manipulating the case behind the scenes
to target my father,
by the time the court finishes
investigating and makes a final ruling,
it will be too late.
I must find out the truth first.
Young Master,
I'll go with you.
No need.
I'll go alone and return quickly.
Stay at the manor and cover for me.
And protect the witness.
Young Master,
please be careful.
Vice Minister of Imperial Observatory,
(Receiving the Mandate
and Establishing the Foundation)
I ordered you to choose
an auspicious day for the royal wedding.
Do you have a result?
Replying to Your Majesty,
based on astrology and birth charts,
I have selected a highly auspicious date
for the marriage.
Please take a look, Your Majesty.
Excellent.
Huayong,
Zhaoning,
one month from now.
This date is indeed an excellent choice.
What do the two of you think?
Your Majesty,
a few days ago, I
was frightened at Gudu Garden.
I beseech Your Majesty
to postpone the wedding for me.
Regarding the incident at Gudu Garden,
as to who set the fire,
Prefect of Jingzhao has already
ordered a thorough investigation.
Commandery Princess Zhaoning,
you need not worry.
Your Majesty,
I am feeling extremely unwell.
I have already asked the imperial
physician to help me recover.
I truly cannot get married right now.
Your Majesty, since that is the case,
let's wait until
the Commandery Princess feels better.
Marriage is a major event.
There is no need to rush it right now.
Thank you for your understanding,
Your Highness.
Very well.
I respect your wishes.
Once Commandery Princess Zhaoning
has recovered,
Minister of Rites,
Vice Minister of Imperial Observatory,
choose another auspicious date.
- Yes, Your Majesty.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
(Ningze Prefecture, Zenan District)
Officers,
the vegetables are quite fresh.
I picked them this morning.
Wash them and deliver them
to the magistrate's office for us.
You're new here, huh?
Who told you
that you could set up a stall here?
Officers, please have mercy.
This is my only way
to make a living and feed my family.
Cut the crap.
Get out of here.
You...
What gives you the right?
Why kick my things and chase me away?
I have no one to rely on,
and my life is worthless.
You won't let me do my only job!
How will I survive?
Arrest this unruly peasant!
Hold on!
In broad daylight,
even if these vendors are at fault,
as officers of the imperial court,
how can you abuse your power
to bully people like this?
Who are you? You dare meddle in
the affairs of the magistrate's office?
I am but a humble scholar.
Though I am an outsider
residing in Zenan,
I absolutely cannot stand by
and watch you
bully the commoners like this.
There are so many troublemakers today.
Take them all back.
- Let's see if you're still this cocky
- How can you arrest people?
when we get to the magistrate's office.
What are you doing?
I'm here to help you.
Who asked for your help?
Let go.
Move.
Hurry up.
Faster.
What are you looking at?
Walk faster.
Why were you
causing trouble on the street
and obstructing official duties?
Officer,
I ran out of travel money,
so I set up a stall to get by.
I was just acting on impulse earlier
and offended you officers.
I admit I was wrong, okay?
Don't play dumb with me.
Speak.
What's your name?
Cui Ergou.
And you?
Lin Tieniu.
I am traveling here for my studies.
I was overcome
with righteous indignation.
That's why I spoke up to help.
I didn't mean to cause trouble.
How many people are in your families?
I'm the only one in my family.
Back home,
I have a bedridden elderly father.
Do you have any relatives
working in the government?
- No.
Anyone in the military?
You two
blocked the road with your stall
and obstructed official duties.
It's not a major crime.
We'll lock you up for three days
as a warning to others.
Cui Jinbai, I'm begging you.
I admit I really shouldn't have pestered
you just to avoid the princess.
You have your future,
your reputation.
Don't want any of that anymore?
Could you stop pestering me?
Is this all you have to say to me?
Yes.
Then could I trouble you
to actually listen to what I'm saying?
I have read extensively since childhood.
My family's teachings, the Four Bonds,
the Three Principles and Five Virtues
have long been etched into my bones.
I also resent myself.
Why have I become so absurd
and ridiculous?
I've tried to cut all ties with you.
But I can't do it.
Are you crazy?
I am crazy.
You're the one who made me lose my mind.
To be reckless
and willingly so.
Why don't we take care
of business first?
Let's investigate
this so-called wrongful imprisonment.
If you were coming over to help me,
why didn't you bring a few more people?
Without His Majesty's decree,
or official documents
from the imperial court,
leaving the capital secretly
is already a serious crime.
If I brought people here
and made a big scene,
would I be helping you or harming you?
You two,
we're short on cells right now.
You didn't commit any major offenses.
So we're releasing you early.
You can leave tomorrow night.
Tomorrow night? Why so soon?
What? You want to celebrate
the Chinese New Year here?
Why would they let us go so easily?
Could it be
they have an ulterior motive?
Just sign and fingerprint this,
and you can go.
(Prisoners: Lin Tieniu, Cui Ergou)
(Guard on Duty: Zhao Wu)
Hurry up down there.
- Make it quick.
- Hurry up.
You guys in the back, hurry up.
Move it!
Put some back into it!
Hurry up!
Move!
Go, go, go!
Move it! What are you looking at?
Hurry up!
Keep moving!
You in the back, hurry up!
Let me tell you something.
You'd better behave.
Hurry up!
Stop dawdling!
Hurry up, you guys in the back!
Stop slacking off! Hurry up!
I wouldn't dare!
I'll never do it again!
See that?
That's what happens
when you try to escape.
You'd better work hard.
If anyone dares to run away,
you'll be in for it.
Move!
You guys, over here.
Grab your tools here.
Hurry up!
Mister...
Where are you from?
Mister,
how did you end up here?
Looks like we won't
get anything out of them.
Don't worry. We'll find another chance.
You there.
You.
Yes, you.
Take off your shirt.
Come work the forge.
Sir,
let me do it.
First time I've seen someone
volunteer for this.
My family used to run a blacksmith shop.
I've been forging iron
since I was a kid.
I'm not used to mining anyway.
Alright, you're up.
Take off your shirt.
Get to the forge.
Hurry up!
Stop dawdling!
Get to work!
Hurry up!
Put your back into it!
Move!
Move faster!
(Duke of Wei's Manor)
Your Highness,
the Crown Prince
has sent another letter.
Read it.
"Day after day,
thoughts of you linger in my heart.
The mountains are green,
the sky is high, and the road is long.
Yet there is no one to meet after dusk.
A...
A moment apart,
and my spirit fades."
Your Highness,
you'd better read it yourself.
(How can a slight unfurrowing of brows
erase the pain in my heart?)
So mushy.
Your Highness,
Jin Shan says there's an urgent matter.
He must see you in person.
Did something happen to Lin?
Your Highness, Young Master
can't leave here without permission,
so he secretly went
to Zenan District to investigate.
Before leaving, he said
if there's no news from him
within five days, he might be trapped.
He also said you are the only person in
the entire imperial capital he trusts,
and that we could ask for your help.
Hurry up!
Sit down.
This should be more comfortable.
Does the wound on your back hurt a lot?
It's nothing.
Just a flesh wound.
It just looks scary, that's all.
Come on, get up and eat!
Get up!
It's mine!
Leave some for me!
Eat up.
They capture people for slave labor
and won't even give us a full meal.
Those beasts.
We still have to work tomorrow.
Try to eat something.
I have no appetite.
I really didn't expect
that in Shunan's territory,
someone would dare
to illegally open a mine,
forge weapons,
and enslave prisoners.
These are capital offenses
strictly forbidden by the court.
Shunan's terrain is complex
and extremely difficult to control.
For them to operate in such a place
on such a massive scale,
the forces behind them
must be formidable.
Right now, conserving our strength
is what matters.
You should eat something.
I really have no appetite.
You're injured.
I practice martial arts year-round,
so I get injured often.
I wouldn't have noticed
if you hadn't mentioned it.
Don't make a big deal out of it, okay?
In front of me,
you don't have to be
the flawless Young Master Bu.
Here.
Everyone knows
that I, Bu Shulin, am a playboy.
I spend my time drinking, partying
and fooling around.
I'm ignorant and incompetent.
Take a good look for yourself.
You, ignorant and incompetent?
You were summoned to the capital
by imperial decree at age nine.
You were essentially a hostage.
Your every move
influenced the court's judgment
of Shunan.
Yet, at such a young age,
you navigated alone among nobles,
civil and military officials,
and even around His Majesty.
You never brought the slightest trouble
to Shunan.
I know
you have your own responsibilities
to shoulder.
This responsibility
is both admirable
and heartbreaking.
If you don't want me
sitting next to you,
I can move further away.
Get some sleep.
I'll keep watch for you.
Your Highness,
Bu Shulin has gone missing in Zenan.
Commandery Princess followed him.
I'll go, too.
No. You haven't fully recovered yet.
Also, we still haven't
found the mastermind
behind the assassins who attacked you
at the lantern festival.
I'm afraid those people
will try to harm you again.
I've ordered Zhao Zhenghao
to keep investigating
the connection
between those assassins and Li Yanhui.
Prepare the carriage. We leave now.
Yes.
Come here.
You memorized all the routes here?
The scale of this place
far exceeds a normal mine.
The illegal forging of weapons
is undeniable proof.
We need to escape quickly
and get the word out
to wipe out this den of thieves.
But the paths here go in all directions.
I can't believe you remembered them all.
My brilliance
is already known to you.
So there's no need for me
to hide it anymore.
If we start from here,
we only need to take out two guards.
Avoid the main mine shaft
and armory on the west side,
and leave through the east passage.
This is the shortest route.
Your brilliance
is on par with mine.
We're quite a match.
Let's go.
Someone's escaping!
After them!
Hurry!
Catch them!
There they are!
Over there!
There are too many of them!
You go first.
No, we leave together.
Listen to me.
Go!
Stop!
Don't run!
Get him!
- That's for running!
Here you go, sir.
Your horse is ready.
Who are you?
I am
(Tang Juan, Magistrate of Zenan)
Tang Juan, Magistrate of Zenan District.
Magistrate of Zenan District?
Guards,
arrest this fugitive.
Throw him in prison
and interrogate him thoroughly.
Yes, sir.
(Zenan District Office)
The Crown Prince?
His Highness must have followed
Commandery Princess here.
Wherever he is,
and whatever he thinks or does
have nothing to do with us.
We need to focus on our business.
Prefect Yu.
(Yu Zao, Prefect of Zenan)
This man is Marquis of Shunan's heir.
How should we deal with him?
Since he already knows about the mine,
we can't give him the chance
to spread the word.
Silence him?
But he's the heir
of the Marquis of Shunan.
In Marquis of Shunan's Manor,
he is the heir.
In the Zenan prison,
he's just a death row inmate.
I understand.
Prefect Yu, Magistrate Tang.
The daughter of Duke Wei,
Commandery Princess Zhaoning
has arrived.
She is already in the front hall.
Commandery Princess Zhaoning?
Why is she here?
What are you waiting for?
I'll get it done immediately.
It seems someone can't wait.
If you kill me,
have you thought
about the consequences?
You must know who I am by now.
If I die in your Zenan prison,
do you think you can get away with it?
Do you think your superiors
will step up and take the blame
or will they throw you
under the bus immediately
as a scapegoat
to appease the Marquis's wrath
and cover up all their crimes?
It's not too late to stop now.
No matter what you say,
this engagement
must be broken.
You are bullying me again.
♪A wall that collapses at a single push♪
It doesn't matter if some things
take a little longer.
I'm willing to wait.
♪I've hidden so many words♪
♪Too reluctant to tell you♪
♪So never uncover♪
♪The sand that slips away
with one grasp♪
♪The flower that withers
after one bloom♪
♪Silently buried deep inside my heart♪
♪Every answer I gave♪
♪Was both bittersweet and absurd♪
♪Hiding my tear-filled eyes
when I hurt you♪
♪How hard it truly was?♪
♪The wounds that healed
with just a little comfort♪
♪The lies made whole
with a single embrace♪
♪Pretending to be brave
as if I'd never been hurt♪
♪It's a shame I never could♪
♪Give you a moon in return♪
♪With the same open heart you loved me♪
♪I've crossed the wasteland of memories♪
♪Never knowing I was lost♪
♪Why don't you take me away?♪
♪Lead me out of this endless game
of hide-and-seek♪
♪You'll never♪
♪Know how much I long to, long to♪
(No animals were harmed
in the making of this film)